<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>servo&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://servomac.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on servo&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2019 18:07:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://servomac.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Books readed in 2019</title>
      <link>https://servomac.github.io/blog/books-readed-in-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2019 18:07:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://servomac.github.io/blog/books-readed-in-2019/</guid>
      <description>October The Intelligent Investor, by Benjamin Graham
August Gang leader for a day, by Sudhir Venkatesh
July Fariña, by Nacho Carretero Pou
June The Manager&amp;rsquo;s Path, by Camille Fournier
February Why smart people make big money mistakes, by Gary Belsky and Thomas Gilovich
January Coaching habit, by Michael Bungay Stanier</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books readed in 2018</title>
      <link>https://servomac.github.io/blog/books-readed-in-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Dec 2018 12:26:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://servomac.github.io/blog/books-readed-in-2018/</guid>
      <description>December The Most Important Thing, by Howard Marks
November Camino de servidumbre, by Friedrich A. Hayek
October Introducción a la inversión, by Javier García de Tiedra González
Gana dinero en bolsa como inversor particular, by David Blanco Galisteo
September Las consecuencias económicas de la paz, by John Mynard Keynes
August Invirtiendo a largo plazo: mi experiencia como inversor, by Francisco García Paramés
July Historia de la Economia, by John Kenneth Galbraith</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books readed in 2017</title>
      <link>https://servomac.github.io/blog/books-readed-in-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 21:23:22 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://servomac.github.io/blog/books-readed-in-2017/</guid>
      <description>December Cartes des de Caubet, by Josep-Joan Rosselló Cuní
November Clean Architecture, by Robert C. Martin
October Matchmakers: The new economics of multisided platforms, by David S. Evans &amp;amp; Richard Schmalensee
September Irresistible APIs, by Kirsten L. Hunter
Homo Deus, by Yuval Noah Harari
Confesions of the Pricing Man, by Hermann Simon
August Practical Statistics for Data Scientists, by Peter Bruce &amp;amp; Andrew Bruce
July Headstrong: 52 Women Who Changed Science-and the World, by Rachel Swaby</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning from imbalanced data</title>
      <link>https://servomac.github.io/blog/learning-from-imbalanced-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 18:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://servomac.github.io/blog/learning-from-imbalanced-data/</guid>
      <description>What is an imbalanced dataset? Most algorithms for machine learning assume that the training set data classes are balanced. But a lot of real world scenarios present classification problems where the involved classes aren&amp;rsquo;t equally represented: one class is composed by a large number of instances, while the other contains a small number of examples. In this case, the learning algorithm may have difficulties learning the concepts representing the minority class.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3 months study guide</title>
      <link>https://servomac.github.io/blog/3-months-study-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2016 18:20:37 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://servomac.github.io/blog/3-months-study-guide/</guid>
      <description>During the next months I will be struggling with a career path shift (i really prefer to say that it&amp;rsquo;s a career fork). Currently I&amp;rsquo;m working as a devops engineer, but I&amp;rsquo;m pivoting to a data science / machine learning developer position. I have always been interested in a wide range of aspects of the computer science, being more a generalist than a specialist (even that market seems to favour specialists in a concrete level of the stack, and I have specialized in distributed systems and web reliability).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books readed in 2016</title>
      <link>https://servomac.github.io/blog/books-readed-in-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2016 19:33:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://servomac.github.io/blog/books-readed-in-2016/</guid>
      <description> December  Data Science for Business, by Foster Provost and Tom Fawcett  November  Refactoring, by Martin Fowler  October  Clean Code, by Robert C. Martin Art of Data Science, by Roger D. Peng and Elizabeth Matsui  September  Sapiens, by Yuval Noah Harari How not to be wrong, by Jordon Ellenberg  August  The second machine age, by Erik Brynjolfsson and Andrew McAfee Doing Data Science, by Cathy O&amp;rsquo;Neil and Rachel Schutt  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>about</title>
      <link>https://servomac.github.io/fixed/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2016 19:21:32 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://servomac.github.io/fixed/about/</guid>
      <description>My name is Toni Pizà. I&amp;rsquo;m a developer with a wide range of interests, mainly involved in algorithmics, web architecture, distributed systems and machine learning. I have a bachelor&amp;rsquo;s degree in Computer Science by the University of the Balearic Islands (UIB), and I have coursed a master degree in Computing by the Polytechnic University of Catalonia (UPC), but i haven&amp;rsquo;t read my master thesis.
I worked as a backend developer and devops engineer.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>